Walter B. Wriston Papers MS134
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
- Articles and Interviews, 1955 -- 2005; 1984 -- 1999; MS134.003; 3.25 Linear Feet; 36 Digital Object(s)
  - On Classified Loans by Walter B. Wriston, The New York Times, 1976-01-30; MS134.003.026.00015 (Box 26)
  - Introduction by Walter B. Wriston, Financial Competition and the Public Interest, 1978; MS134.003.026.00016; Wriston, Walter B. (Box 26)
    Walter Wriston wrote the introduction for the book Financial Competition and the Public Interest by Will R. Sparks.
    Banks and banking
  - Repressing Economic News by Walter B. Wriston, The Wall Street Journal, 1979-05-04; MS134.003.026.00017; Wriston, Walter B. (Box 26)
    Inflation (Finance) United States
  - LDCs Just Need a Little Help From Their Friends by Walter B. Wriston, The Wall Street Journal, 1984-03-13; MS134.003.026.00018; Wriston, Walter B. (Box 26)
    Developing countries
  - Microseconds and Macropolicy by Walter B. Wriston, Regulation: AEI [American Enterprise Institute] Journal on Government and Society, 1985-03 -- 1985-04; MS134.003.026.00019 (Box 26)
  - Foreword by Walter B. Wriston, Citibank:1812-1970, 1985-05-28; MS134.003.026.00020 (Box 26)
    Walter Wriston wrote the foreword for the book Citibank: 1812-1970 by Harold van B. Cleveland and Thomas F. Huertas.
  - Article for German Publication, 1985-07-11; MS134.003.026.00021 (Box 26)
  - In Search of a Money Standard: We Have One: It Comes in a Tube by Walter B. Wriston, The Wall Street Journal, 1985-11-12; MS134.003.026.00022; Wriston, Walter B. (Box 26)
    Free enterprise; Banks and banking, International; Technology
  - Chapter 11 is a Possible Option In My Opinion by Walter B. Wriston, The New York Times, 1985-12-15; MS134.003.026.00023 (Box 26)
  - The World According to Walter by Walter B. Wriston, Harvard Business Review, 1986-01 -- 1986-02; MS134.003.026.00024; Wriston, Walter B. (Box 26)
    International economic relations; Banks and banking; Risk
  - Economic Freedom Receives a Boost by Walter B. Wriston, The New York Times, 1986-04-15; MS134.003.026.00025; Wriston, Walter B. (Box 26)
    Free enterprise; Democracy
  - Dr. Doom Takes Dark View of Deregulation by Walter B. Wriston, The Wall Street Journal, 1986-04-14 -- 1986-05-12; MS134.003.026.00026; Wriston, Walter B. (Box 26)
    The article was published May 12, 1986.
    Deregulation; Book Reviews
  - The Fight for Survival by Walter B. Wriston, The Economist Financial Report, 1986-06-26 -- 1986-07-10; MS134.003.026.00027; Wriston, Walter B. (Box 26)
    Deregulation; Banks and banking
  - Remeasuring the Economy by Walter B. Wriston, Economic Impact, 1985 -- 1986-09-04; MS134.003.026.00028 (Box 26)
    The article was published in 1986. The article was originally prepared as a speech "Gnomons, Words and Policies" given to the Executive Club May 8, 1985. See UA069.005.DO.00220.
  - The Information Explosion by Walter B. Wriston, Reuters World, 1986-11; MS134.003.026.00029 (Box 26)
  - Personal Reflections on the State of the Board by James Kristie, Directors & Boards, Fall, 1986; MS134.003.026.00030 (Box 26)
  - Walter Wriston: Was I exacting? Sure. Was I occasionally sarcastic? Of Course by Walter B. Wriston, Institutional Investor, 1987-06; MS134.003.027.00001 (Box 27)
  - Doing Business in an Age of Electronic Miracles and Wonder by Walter B. Wriston, American Banker, 1987-06-22; MS134.003.027.00002 (Box 27)
  - Delineating the Dead Hand of the Past by Walter B. Wriston, The Wall Street Journal, 1987-05-18 -- 1987-06-24; MS134.003.027.00003; Wriston, Walter B. (Box 27)
    The article was published June 24, 1987.
    Politics; Book Reviews
  - Democracy, Dollars, and Dialectic by Walter B. Wriston, American Politics, 1987-04-03 -- 1987-08-03; MS134.003.027.00004; Wriston, Walter B. (Box 27)
    The article was published July 1987.
    Monetary policy United States
  - Do You Have a Formal Information Strategy? by Walter B. Wriston, Financial Executive, 1987-11 -- 1987-12; MS134.003.027.00005 (Box 27)
  - A New Kind of Speech by Walter B. Wriston, Forbes, 1987-11 -- 1987-12-14; MS134.003.027.00006 (Box 27)
    The article was published December 14, 1987.
    Technology; Stock exchanges; International finance
  - Introduction to President Reagan's Remarks to the Students and Faculty of Moscow State University by Walter B. Wriston, Manhattan Institute, 1988-05-31 -- 1988-12-15; MS134.003.027.00007 (Box 27)
  - Technology and Sovereignty by Walter B. Wriston, Foreign Affairs, 1988; MS134.003.027.00008 (Box 27)
    1988/1989
  - On Track With the Deficit by Walter. B. Wriston, The Wall Street Journal, 1989-01-06 -- 1989-03-13; MS134.003.027.00009; Wriston, Walter B. (Box 27)
    The article was published January 6, 1989.
    Budget deficits United States
  - Stars of the 1980s Cast Their Light by Myron Magnet, Fortune, 1989-07-03; MS134.003.027.00010 (Box 27)
  - Technology and Direct Marketing: Consumers Have Responded Favorably by Walter B. Wriston, Vital Speeches of the Day, 1989-09-01; MS134.003.027.00011; Wriston, Walter B. (Box 27)
    Business; Information technology
  - Measure [Not Published], 1996; MS134.003.027.00012 (Box 27)
    This date is approximate.
  - The State of American Management by Walter B. Wriston, Harvard Business Review, 1989-10-17 -- 1990-02; MS134.003.027.00013 (Box 27)
    The article was published January/February 1990.
  - The Beltway-Media Complex by Walter B. Wriston, The Wall Street Journal, 1990-10-29; MS134.003.027.00014; Wriston, Walter B. (Box 27)
    Journalism; Press and politics
  - No Wonder Banks Fail by Walter B. Wriston, The Wall Street Journal, 1990-12-14 -- 1990-12-21; MS134.003.027.00015; Wriston, Walter B. (Box 27)
    The article was published December 19, 1990.
    Banks and banking; Investments
  - Letter to the Editor from Walter B. Wriston, New York Times, 1991-07-27; MS134.003.027.00016 (Box 27)
  - Visions 2000 by Walter B. Wriston, Chief Executive, 1988-03-30 -- 1991-12; MS134.003.027.00017 (Box 27)
    The article was published November/December 1991.
  - Saving the Banks: Banks' Weaknesses Are a Regulatory Illusion by Walter B. Wriston, The Wall Street Journal, 1992-01-30 -- 1992-02-07; MS134.003.027.00018; Wriston, Walter B. (Box 27)
    The article was published February 7, 1992.
    Banks and banking-Goverment policy
  - 'Market to Market': Wild Accountants' Crazy Idea by Walter B. Wriston, The Wall Street Journal, 1992-04-29 -- 1992-06-11; MS134.003.027.00019; Wriston, Walter B. (Box 27)
    The article was published June 11, 1992.
    Current value accounting; Accounting
  - The Twilight of Sovereignty by Walter B. Wriston & Henry Grunwald, RSA [Royal Society for the encouragement of Arts, Manufacturers & Commerce] Journal, 1992-08 -- 1992-09; MS134.003.027.00020; Wriston, Walter B.; Grunwald, Henry (Box 27)
    Political science; Information technology
  - The Decline of the Central Bankers by Walter B. Wriston, The New York Times, 1992-09-20; MS134.003.027.00021 (Box 27)
  - The Twilight of Sovereignty and the Information Standard by Walter B. Wriston, The American Enterprise, 1992-09 -- 1992-10; MS134.003.027.00022 (Box 27)
  - Twilight of Sovereignty by Walter Wriston, The Commonwealth: The Weekly Publication of the Commonwealth Club of California, 1992-11-23; MS134.003.027.00023 (Box 27)
  - Big Brother, We Are Watching You by Walter B. Wriston, Forbes, 1992-12-02 -- 1993-01-04; MS134.003.027.00024; Wriston, Walter B.; Grunwald, Henry (Box 27)
    The article was published January 4, 1993.
    Technology; Economic policy
  - The Wall Street Journal Articles [Not Published], 1992-03-02 -- 1993-02-19; MS134.003.027.00025 (Box 27)
  - Clintonomics: The Information Revolution and the New Global Market Economy by Walter B. Wriston, Vital Speeches of the Day, 1993-04-01; MS134.003.028.00001 (Box 28)
  - Twilight of Sovereignty by Walter B. Wriston, The Fletcher Forum of World Affairs, Summer, 1993; MS134.003.028.00002 (Box 28)
  - Twilight of Sovereignty by Walter B. Wriston, The Fletcher Forum of World Affairs, Summer, 1993; MS134.003.028.00003 (Box 28)
  - Off by a Factor of Four by Walter B. Wriston, Forbes, 1993-05-26 -- 1993-06-21; MS134.003.028.00004; Wriston, Walter B. (Box 28)
    The article was published June 21, 1993.
    Economic policy
  - Clintonomics: The Information Society and the New Global Market Economy by Walter B. Wriston, Executive Speeches, 1993-04-27 -- 1993-07; MS134.003.028.00005; Wriston, Walter B. (Box 28)
    The article was published June/July 1993.
    Technology; Politics
  - Deficit Thinking by Walter B. Wriston, Far Eastern Economic Review, 1993-06-16 -- 1993-07-22; MS134.003.028.00006 (Box 28)
    The article was published July 22, 1993.
  - To Market, To Market by Walter B. Wriston, Washington Post, 1993-10-03 -- 1993-11-07; MS134.003.028.00007 (Box 28)
    The article was published November 7, 1993.
  - Advice for the New Mayor comments by Walter B. Wriston, City Journal, 1993-11-22 -- 1994; MS134.003.028.00008 (Box 28)
    The article was published in Winter 1994.
  - Forbes Articles [Not Published], 1985-07-22 -- 1994; MS134.003.028.00009 (Box 28)
  - The Independent Man and the Transference Machine by Walter B. Wriston, Executive Speeches, 1994-08 -- 1994-09; MS134.003.028.00010; Wriston, Walter B. (Box 28)
    Politics and government; Ethics; Education
  - Bashing Japan with Flawed Figures by Walter B. Wriston, Washington Post, 1994-08-04 -- 1994-10-12; MS134.003.028.00011 (Box 28)
    The article was published August 4, 1994.
  - The Inevitable Global Conversation by Walter B. Wriston, Media Studies Journal, Winter, 1994; MS134.003.028.00012 (Box 28)
  - A Failure of Management by Walter B. Wriston, Sternbusiness, 1995; MS134.003.028.00013 (Box 28)
  - Walter Wriston (proposal to Privatize the World Bank) by Walter B. Wriston, The National Interest, 1995-04-06 -- 1995-04-13; MS134.003.028.00014 (Box 28)
    The article was published Summer 1995.
  - Incredible Future by Walter B. Wriston, Executive Excellence, 1995-11; MS134.003.028.00015 (Box 28)
  - Money: Back to the Future? by Walter B. Wriston, The Wall Street Journal, 1995-10-11 -- 1995-11-24; MS134.003.028.00016; Wriston, Walter B. (Box 28)
    The article was published November 24, 1995.
    Banks and banking-Technological innovation
  - Two Deficits that Just Don't Matter by Walter B. Wriston and Charles Wolf Jr., The Wall Street Journal, 1997-06-02 -- 1997-06-04; MS134.003.028.00017; Wriston, Walter B.; Wolf, Charles, Jr. (Box 28)
    The article was published June 19, 1997.
    Budget deficits United States; Economic indicators
  - Bits, Bytes, and Diplomacy by Walter B. Wriston, PeaceWorks, 1997-09; MS134.003.028.00018 (Box 28)
  - Bits, Bytes, and Diplomacy by Walter B. Wriston, Foreign Affairs, 1997-07-14 -- 1997-10; MS134.003.028.00019 (Box 28)
  - Bits, Bytes, and Diplomacy by Walter B. Wriston, Foreign Affairs, 1997-09 -- 1997-10; MS134.003.029.00001 (Box MS134 Shared 3)
  - Dumb Networks and Smart Capital by Walter B. Wriston, The Cato Journal, 1998; MS134.003.029.00002 (Box MS134 Shared 3)
  - Who Needs the IMF? by George P. Shultz, William E. Simon, and Walter B. Wriston, Hoover Digest, 1998; MS134.003.029.00003 (Box MS134 Shared 3)
  - Who Needs the IMF? by George P. Shultz, William E. Simon, and Walter B. Wriston, The Wall Street Journal, 1998-01-22 -- 1998-02-03; MS134.003.029.00004; Wriston, Walter B.; Schultz, George P.; Simon, William E. (Box MS134 Shared 3)
    The article was published February 3, 1998.
    Finance; International Monetary Fund
  - Issues: What are the implications of E-cash for Monetary policy? by Walter B. Wriston, Economic Times of New Delhi, 1998-12-15; MS134.003.029.00005 (Box MS134 Shared 3)
  - Save to Paste [Not Published], 1999; MS134.003.029.00006 (Box MS134 Shared 3)
  - The Millennium--The Most Influential Innovations of the Millennium, One Paragraph by Walter B. Wriston, The Wall Street Journal, 1999-01-11; MS134.003.029.00007 (Box MS134 Shared 3)
  - Who Needs the IMF? by George P. Shultz, William E. Simon, and Walter B. Wriston, The International Monetary Fund-Financial Medic to the World? A Primer on Mission, Operations, and Public Policy Issues, 1999; MS134.003.029.00008 (Box MS134 Shared 3)
  - Letter to the Editor from Walter B. Wriston, The New York Times, 2000-04-24; MS134.003.029.00009 (Box MS134 Shared 3)
  - Review of Neal Stephenson's Cryptonomicon, 2000-06-21; MS134.003.029.00010 (Box MS134 Shared 3)
  - Trust [Not Published], 2000-11-17; MS134.003.029.00011 (Box MS134 Shared 3)
  - Economics [Not Published], 2001; MS134.003.029.00012 (Box MS134 Shared 3)
  - You Call This Debt Reduction? by Walter B. Wriston, The Wall Street Journal, 2001-03-28 -- 2001-04-30; MS134.003.029.00013; Wriston, Walter B. (Box MS134 Shared 3)
    The article was published April 27, 2001.
  - The Voice of Experience by Walter B. Wriston, American Way, 2001-07-01; MS134.003.029.00014; Wriston, Walter B. (Box MS134 Shared 3)
  - Banking Against Disaster by Walter B. Wriston, The New York Times, 1982-09-14 -- 2002-04-12; MS134.003.029.00015; Wriston, Walter B. (Box MS134 Shared 3)
    The article was published September 14, 1982.
    Banks and banking, International; Developing countries
  - The Solution to Scandals? Simpler Rules by Walter B. Wriston, The Wall Street Journal, 2002-07-31 -- 2002-08-01; MS134.003.029.00016; Wriston, Walter B. (Box MS134 Shared 3)
    The article was published August 5, 2002.
    Accounting; Regulation; International Accounting Standards Board
  - Financial Times Article [Not Published], 2002-12-24 -- 2002-12-27; MS134.003.029.00017 (Box MS134 Shared 3)
  - Silver Blaze [Not Published], March 20-24, 2003-03-20 -- 2003-03-24; MS134.003.029.00018 (Box MS134 Shared 3)
  - Other People's Money by Walter B. Wriston, DisclosureResource.com Resources & Education-Expert Articles, 2002-06-17 -- 2003-10-30; MS134.003.029.00019 (Box MS134 Shared 3)
  - Trashing Patriots by Walter B. Wriston, The Wall Street Journal, [Not Published], 2003-11-05 -- 2003-11-21; MS134.003.029.00020 (Box MS134 Shared 3)
  - Freedom and Democracy in the Information Age by Walter B. Wriston, Technology in Society, 2003 -- 2004-10-16; MS134.003.029.00021; Wriston, Walter B. (Box MS134 Shared 3)
    The article was published in 2004.
    Information technology; Politics
  - Ever Heard of Insourcing by Walter B. Wriston, The Wall Street Journal, 2003-04-20 -- 2004-03-04; MS134.003.029.00022 (Box MS134 Shared 3)
    The article was published March 24, 2004.
  - New York crisis: save our city, 2003-05-09; MS134.003.029.00023; Wriston, Walter B.; Carey, Hugh; Gilder, Richard; Hemmerdinger, H. Dale; Hartog, Roger; Rohatyn, Felix G.
    Municipal finance; Fiscal spending
  - A code of our own, 2003-01-16; MS134.003.029.00024; Wriston, Walter B.
    Business ethics; Industrial policy
  - [Bits, Bytes, and Balance Sheets- correspondence and publishing material], MS134.003.040.00016 (Box MS134 Shared 2)
  - Walter Wriston on Walter Wriston by Gil Kaplan, Institutional Investor [Includes Roger Hertog and Henry Kissenger letters], 1975; MS134.003.040.00021 (Box MS134 Shared 2)
  - If you ask me: A global banker reflects on our times, 1980; MS134.003.040.00022 (Box MS134 Shared 2)
  - ['Risk,' the American Law Institute, and the Corporate Director draft], 1986-11-11; MS134.003.040.00023 (Box MS134 Shared 2)
  - ['Risk,' the American Law Institute, and the Corporate Director] [bound volume "The American Law Institute and Corporate Governance], 1987-01; MS134.003.040.00024 (Box MS134 Shared 2)
  - [Visions 2000] New York Times, 1988-03-30; MS134.003.040.00025 (Box MS134 Shared 2)
  - [Comments on Twilight of Sovereignty for American Public Media] Public Radio, 1992-09-16; MS134.003.040.00026 (Box MS134 Shared 2)
  - [Clintonomics] Fortune, 1992-11; MS134.003.040.00027 (Box MS134 Shared 2)
  - [Clintonomics] Fortune article, 1992-11; MS134.003.040.00028 (Box MS134 Shared 2)
  - [Clintonomics] Fortune Piece, 1992-11; MS134.003.040.00029 (Box MS134 Shared 2)
  - [Clintonomics] Forbes-DecL9, 1992-12; MS134.003.040.00030 (Box MS134 Shared 2)
  - [Clintonomics] Forbes, 1992-12; MS134.003.040.00031 (Box MS134 Shared 2)
  - [Clintonomics] Clinton, 1993-02; MS134.003.040.00032 (Box MS134 Shared 2)
  - [Clintonomics] Clinton's Program, 1993-03; MS134.003.040.00033 (Box MS134 Shared 2)
  - Forbes #1, 1993-05-26; MS134.003.040.00034 (Box MS134 Shared 2)
  - [Deficit Thinking] Budget, 1993-07-22; MS134.003.040.00035 (Box MS134 Shared 2)
  - [Deficit Thinking] Far East article, 1993-07-22; MS134.003.040.00036 (Box MS134 Shared 2)
  - [Review of] Revolution on Wall Street, 1993-10-21; MS134.003.040.00037 (Box MS134 Shared 2)
  - [Advice for the New Mayor] City Journal, 1994; MS134.003.040.00038 (Box MS134 Shared 2)
  - [Advice for the New Mayor] Memo to Mayor, 1994; MS134.003.040.00039 (Box MS134 Shared 2)
  - [Bashing Japan with Flawed Figures] Forbes article, 1994-08-04; MS134.003.040.00040 (Box MS134 Shared 2)
  - [Money: Back to the Future?] Wall St Journal, 1995-11-24; MS134.003.040.00041 (Box MS134 Shared 2)
  - [Dumb Networks and Smart Capital] Cato, 1998; MS134.003.040.00042 (Box MS134 Shared 2)
  - Save to Paste, 1999; MS134.003.040.00043 (Box MS134 Shared 2)
  - [Review of Neal Stephenson's Cryptonomicon] Crypto, 2000-06-21; MS134.003.040.00044 (Box MS134 Shared 2)
  - [Trust] Turst, 2000-11-17; MS134.003.040.00045 (Box MS134 Shared 2)
  - Accounting, 2002; MS134.003.040.00046 (Box MS134 Shared 2)
  - Addendum about stock, 2002; MS134.003.040.00047 (Box MS134 Shared 2)
  - wbw61102, 2002-06-11; MS134.003.040.00048 (Box MS134 Shared 2)
  - [Other People's Money] whitepaper1, 2002-07; MS134.003.040.00049 (Box MS134 Shared 2)
  - [Other People's Money] whitepaper2, 2002-07; MS134.003.040.00050 (Box MS134 Shared 2)
  - [Other People's Money] Other People's Money71102, 2002-07-11; MS134.003.040.00051 (Box MS134 Shared 2)
  - Politically Correct vs Accurate Earnings, 2002-08; MS134.003.040.00052 (Box MS134 Shared 2)
  - [Politically Correct vs Accurate Earnings] stock options, 2002-08; MS134.003.040.00053 (Box MS134 Shared 2)
  - [Other People's Money] WalterWr.rtf, 2002-09; MS134.003.040.00054 (Box MS134 Shared 2)
  - [Other People's Money] WalterWr.rtf 6, 2002-09; MS134.003.040.00055 (Box MS134 Shared 2)
  - [Other People's Money] Wriston oped-1.rtf, 2002-09; MS134.003.040.00056 (Box MS134 Shared 2)
  - [Other People's Money] Wriston other people's money 4, 2002-09; MS134.003.040.00057 (Box MS134 Shared 2)
  - wbw92702, 2002-09-27; MS134.003.040.00058 (Box MS134 Shared 2)
  - [Financial Times Article] FTArticl.doc, 2002-12-24 -- 2002-12-27; MS134.003.040.00059 (Box MS134 Shared 2)
  - [Financial Times Article] Financial Times Articles122402, 2002-12-24 -- 2002-12-27; MS134.003.040.00060 (Box MS134 Shared 2)
  - [Silver Blaze] City, 2003-03-19; MS134.003.041.00001 (Box MS134 Shared 4)
  - [Silver Blaze] Silverblaze31903, 2003-03-19; MS134.003.041.00002 (Box MS134 Shared 4)
  - [Silver Blaze] Silverblazetestdocu, 2003-03-19; MS134.003.041.00003 (Box MS134 Shared 4)
  - Trashing Patriots, 2003-11; MS134.003.041.00004 (Box MS134 Shared 4)
  - [Trashing Patriots] Conflict of Interest, 2003-11; MS134.003.041.00005 (Box MS134 Shared 4)
  - [Trashing Patriots] Trashing, 2003-11; MS134.003.041.00006 (Box MS134 Shared 4)
  - [Trashing Patriots] Trashing 111903, 2003-11; MS134.003.041.00007 (Box MS134 Shared 4)
  - [Trashing Patriots] Trashing Patriots111903, 2003-11; MS134.003.041.00008 (Box MS134 Shared 4)
  - [Trashing Patriots] Trashing Patriots12203, 2003-11; MS134.003.041.00009 (Box MS134 Shared 4)
  - [Trashing Patriots] trashingpatriots12303, 2003-11; MS134.003.041.00010 (Box MS134 Shared 4)
  - [Trashing Patriots] Trashi~4.doc, 2003-11; MS134.003.041.00011 (Box MS134 Shared 4)
  - [Ever heard of insourcing?] Jobs, 2004-03-24; MS134.003.041.00012 (Box MS134 Shared 4)
  - [Ever heard of insourcing?] Jobs3404, 2004-03-24; MS134.003.041.00013 (Box MS134 Shared 4)
  - [Ever heard of insourcing?] Jobs3404.doc, 2004-03-24; MS134.003.041.00014 (Box MS134 Shared 4)
  - Freedom and Democracy in the Information Age, 2004-04 -- 2004-08; MS134.003.041.00015 (Box MS134 Shared 4)
- Audiovisual Media, 1950 -- 2008; 1982 -- 2004; MS134.004; 1.5 Linear Feet
  This series contains audiovisual media, predominately DVDs and CDs, of interviews and speeches by Walter B. Wriston between 1982-2005. Also included are DVDs collected by Wriston about economics, banking, and the various organizations with which he was affiliated. This series includes Wriston's interviews on the Idea Channel with Bob Chitester, Herbert Pardes, Hugh Carey, Robert D. McTeer, Jr., Charles Brunie, and Peter W. Huber. Wriston also appeared on Face the Nation, Meet the Press, Lou Dobbs Tonight, Wall Street Week with Louis Rukeyser, Telecommunications & Information Revolution, and a PBS show called "Electric Money." Wriston's Presidential Medal of Freedom Award is commemorated by a DVD of the presentation ceremony and a DVD created by Citigroup, honoring Wriston. Also included is a DVD of Wriston's convocation speech for Tufts University's Fletcher School of Law and Diplomacy in 2003. Wriston was unable to attend the ceremony and his speech was read by Academic Dean Lisa Lynch.
  There is also a CD-ROM containing copies of files extracted from Wriston's computers in New York City and Connecticut. The majority of the files are drafts of Wriston's books "Twilight of Sovereignty" and "Bites, Bytes, and Balance Sheets", as well as drafts of speeches, articles, and letters. The files are in IBM and MAC formats and the date of last modification ranges from 1989-2006. In addition to Wriston's computer files, the CD-ROM includes spreadsheets and word files created by Kurt Willett to assist in the transfer of documents and the creation of a website dedicated to Walter B. Wriston. The spreadsheets list the file name, a description of the file, the date the file was last modified, the size, the original location of the file, and file type.
  The audiovisual materials in this series are arranged by media type, then chronologically, with material from the 2009 donation added as a second run at the end of the series.
  - [Draft of The World Corporation-New Weight in an Old Balance], 1973; MS134.004.030.00001 (Case 30)
    This audio CD is a copy made by VIDIPAX. The CD is labeled with the job number VIDIPAX JOB #5200 REEL #9 AUDIO CD. The CD is a Verbatim DataLifePlus CD-R. The file type is Winamp media. The recording is an early draft of a speech by Walter Wriston. A final draft of the speech is in Series 1, box 2, and item #00022.
    compact disc
  - Walter B. Wriston Chairman & CEO-Citibank, Face The Nation, 1982-12-05; MS134.004.030.00002 (Case 30)
    This audio CD is a copy made by VIDIPAX. The CD is labeled with the job number VIDIPAX JOB #5386 REEL #001. The CD is a Fujifilm CD-R. The file type is Winamp media. Also written on the CD is The CBS Television Network The CBS Radio Network.
  - Risk - Walter Wriston Edited Voice, 1986; MS134.004.030.00003 (Case 30)
    This audio CD is a copy made by VIDIPAX. The CD is labeled with the job number VIDIPAX JOB #5386 REEL #003. The CD is a Fujifilm CD-R. The file type is Winamp media. Track One is audio clips used in an adaptation of Risk and Other Four Letter Words. It is read by Mr. Wriston. Track Two is an interview for a book on women in the business world
  - Risk and Other Four Letter Words, 1986; MS134.004.030.00004 (Case 30)
    This audio CD is a copy made by VIDIPAX. The CD is labeled with the job number VIDIPAX JOB #5200 REEL #1 AUDIO CD. The CD is a Verbatim DataLifePlus CD-R. The file type is Winamp media. The recording is an audio adaptation of Risk and Other Four Letter Words by Walter Wriston. It is read alternately by Walter Wriston and an unidentified man.